<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AFL on Daily Fantasy Sports Australia</title>
    <link>/tags/afl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AFL on Daily Fantasy Sports Australia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/afl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Can You Be Profitable Playing AFL DFS?</title>
      <link>/blog/2021/07/18/2021-07-18-can-you-be-profitable-playing-afl-dfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021/07/18/2021-07-18-can-you-be-profitable-playing-afl-dfs/</guid>
      <description>I’m confident in saying that 99% of people who read this blog post have at some point dreamt of turning their AFL DFS hobby into a full time income stream. How practical though is that dream in the current landscape? Draftkings and Fanduel offer up eye-watering prizes for those playing US sports but AFL tournaments on Draftstars rarely offer up more than $75,000 prize pools with first place usually taking home less than $10,000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Player Clustering - Advanced Defence v Position</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/08/23/2020-08-17-player-clustering-advanced-defence-v-position/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/08/23/2020-08-17-player-clustering-advanced-defence-v-position/</guid>
      <description>Defence v Position Defence vs Position (or DVP) is a common tool used throughout the Fantasy Sports Industry. The tool has varying levels of importance depending on which sport you are playing. Sports like NBA or NFL lend themselves very well to DVP as there are specific one-on-one matchups that are predictable from one game to the next and player’s roles are highly consistent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defining Draftstars Player Value</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/08/11/defining-draftstars-player-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/08/11/defining-draftstars-player-value/</guid>
      <description>What is Value? A popular way to try normalise player performance in the Fantasy Sports community is to define it in terms of a multiple of their salary. For example, if Tom Mitchell is priced at $15,000 and scores 105 fantasy points then he’s deemed to have returned 7.00x his salary, e.g. (105 / 15,000) * 1000 = 7.00x.
This common strategy gives coaches the ability to compare players across a range of salaries and make a decision on who they think is the best value play for their lineup.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>